good morning Skokie's good morning so
you know um I work in the self-driving
car industry so as part of this is kind
of gonna be my industry commentary I've
been spending the morning watching some
of our competitors videos and I'll give
you kind of what my thoughts are on them
so maybe we'll start with this one so
this is the mole
lacking sleep not something the
last-minute good morning so this is the
mobile like you know terms of my music I
try to watch all these things will fix
better I do so mobile actually is one of
the least high P players in the game no
no I co always actually one of the least
hyping players in the game they had
noticed a few interesting things in this
in this presentation I'm so first off
they're going back to the after market
they have this thing called the mobile I
connect 8 and it looks suspiciously like
a neon you're like a ram in the
aftermarket why you don't program it I
do a lot of programming so yeah this is
this is an interesting play for mobile I
like there they're selling an
aftermarket thing to fleets so if you
guys don't know there's a company called
nada which is doing something similar so
no no builds this little camera thing I
believe it has a Snapdragon 820 in it we
can push them out and it's kind of like
a cloud based dash cam really very
similar to ours I met with them at CES
last year I visited that little booth
man she spoke with Gabby Holsworth
Travis khalaq Nick's ex-girlfriend so
that was kind of interesting but yeah so
let's go back to this mobile I also
announced me to be honest
they're 2018 plans look very similar to
ours and I don't know if I should be
happy about this or concerned by this
but they talked about level 2 plus
really
so they show on the left side there
showing map so these these lanes here
coming from the map and these lanes are
coming from sensing I'm so we're gonna
roll out pretty much the exact same
thing we're gonna have our own comment i
HD maps which we're gonna open source
before the end of the year and they'll
have they'll have telev lanes and
they're not have features to do precise
localization and then kind of you know
where to drive from the map so mobile is
calling this level 2 plus they're
talking about doing traffic lights in
the exact same way we are about as a as
a quote where he literally says but the
hard part is not detecting the traffic
light the hard part is figuring out what
traffic lights apply to you and that's
of course true so yeah there's that now
I can't find a better video for lip lift
inactive so first off to understand
active used to be Delfy so they've kind
of rebranded their self-driving division
in the same way Google we branded their
self-driving division as way mo um so
lift and active bring Robo taxis to CES
and a lot of companies have announced
partnerships with lyft the truth about
these partnerships is my understanding
is like there's no lift technology being
used basically whenever someone
announces a partnership with lyft all
that means is that they're putting their
cars on the lift network effectively
they're signing up their autonomous cars
with safety drivers to be lyft drivers
you know we have this obviously no
partnership we have quite a few people
with with with open pilot driving for
driving on the lyft and uber networks so
I'm important to be clear about what
that
so let's see what's going on here that's
not the car I've seen them have before
before they used to have like SUV like
things some BMW interesting they always
focus on experience I'm not exactly sure
why this is view as the difficult part
so what Delfy had last year was lied
hours around that car I think it's
pretty much the same thing what's
important to look at is their displays
because if they have any display at all
you can glean a whole lot of subtle so
let's see what this is here we have a
dog looks like a fella named puck and
then we have a camera there and they
probably have a radar in there as well
that you can't see behind the plastic
know about the autopilot Alexa so here's
another puck in the I think that's a
puck I mean I guess it could be a
different lighter I don't know okay
let's so let's let's break this down so
it looks like what they're doing is
they've kind of no crowd source those
lane things this looks very similar to
the display that that Delfy showed last
time they clearly have a lidar in the
car because these dots here are coming
from the lidar see that these dots on
the back of the car from the lidar
they're tracking their lead car very
explicitly they have a traffic light
here it's not connection to other cars I
promise you it's not that actually as
far as like actual demos go Delfy active
shows prettily the most impressive one
at CES turn the phone
so the experience doesn't matter this is
what's interesting they have this thing
up here called called manual I'm not
sure how much I can I can say about this
cuz I have actually been for a ride in
this car
it's interesting that they've switched
to BMWs - that must be because of the
why are they do I have orientation lock
then I turn it off but yeah so any any
more things people saw it - yes that we
kind of want to break down its kind of
just a chill I don't have that much um
behavioral cloning doesn't work but we
have a solution to it I'm not gonna go
too much into the details of that but if
the new models work the new models are
gonna be insanely good because they're
not gonna require much automatic
ground-truthing at all
maybe the automatic ground truth or is
much simpler which a lot of the bugs
that exists an open pilot we're at like
drifts out of a lane their bugs in the
automatic ground truth are so let's
check out let's check out AI motive I
wrote in their car last year at CES they
don't have any sort of nd eyes with up
or anything so we can we can say
whatever we want about them I generally
like AI motive look I'm being nice to
people in this periscope yes 20 20 18
I'd if I know has any companies they
want to shout out in the comments will
kind of go through them on will showcase
progress this is useless videos videos
no that was last year different was oh
here we go
a motive at CES day one so this is the
first time I've seen it yeah they had
the same stand last year it's pretty
nice stand
[Music]
show me an actual demo um we can also
break down if you guys haven't watched
the the Nvidia event the Nvidia event is
is interesting as well see what is this
video
this is alt so and videos announcing
these new these new these new hardware
things now my view on it basically is
kind of like why it's in pretty you're
gonna win well the thing about Nvidia is
they're just not going to lose everybody
every same car manufacturer right now
should be buying and videos latest
hardware sticking it in their car and
making sure they can ot hang it it seems
like Tesla's the only one actually smart
enough to do this but when you look at
these things that Nvidia has okay so
first off they show it they show a demo
of a car driving they show a seven-mile
Drive demo but they did show a demo good
morning we're just going through it
we're going we're busting high puts
Kofi's yeah okay so they do this they do
this eight mile autonomous route to New
Jersey the hormone is not too expensive
unless you're an auto manufacturer it's
just kind of useless like there's no
reason that you're better off using
Nvidia's dedicated hardware overusing
like a computer with an NVIDIA GPU well
Wilhite busting let's go peace um so
they have this eight mile autonomous
route we were looking at what it's they
don't really show it they show it
running on like their little thing to my
guess is it's highly localization based
and then they probably have like it's
probably all localization Tom and then
you can just use any sort of like Yolo
net
the Carson CEOs that's a good video
video H yeah K F on the board is for the
Kalman filter which home yes how is how
does the Kalman filter integration
coming no we got it we kind of integrate
it into that into the you know but
that's gotta go I gotta do that okay
here we go perfect on a good click so we
can look at yeah so let's look at let's
look at this this like on the screen
display right yeah they also I love when
they do this they didn't blur out their
screen so the screen is actually down
here so it is running on drive works um
[Music]
let's see if we can get any information
about what it's doing so that Lane that
line is very smooth I really doubt that
that's coming from vision I think it has
to be coming from localization I'm so
you know we talked about these cars
they're actually really just line
following robots it line follows well on
the turns it's usually a real giveaway
whether it's vision based or not I mean
the trick is to find something that
that's not even in the visual scene like
this is how you can bust drive that AI
video is appallingly bad
so they're driving here I've got a
little inch forward at the stop sign and
people think oh that's tricky behavior
no it's just hard coded and like this
they'd like the demo route that they do
and then they they localize they
probably use a bit of vision to localize
- I don't see Lars on the car so the way
companies like crews are doing it is
they have our version of that shit work
we don't go over with the scope ease so
yeah they're not showing vehicle
detection and stuff the real way to
really bust these people is to extract
their video and play it in real time
yeah it's I mean it's all about hype
right it's all about showing high P
demos we might even have a high B demo
plan who wants to see , level four right
Oh
Oh which reminds me okay you're ready
for the worst one let's see if we can
find that there were no level four video
we were making fun of this one around
the office ah yes here we go okay so L
symbiotic self-driving car tempo whose
headlights change color when it's
self-driving you know that's bad now
there's actually a video of them driving
with the journalists in this car and
right there is this this one's bad well
so a few things are bad about it
Wow Wow look at that you can you can set
the music with your phone wow it's the
future all right
so this isn't the one I saw the one that
they show good morning
we're hype bustin with Scopus but we're
going to go through our competitors CES
videos I'm trying I'm trying to find
that Renault level 4 video though the
really bad one it was like Car Talk they
actually let a journalist sit in the
driver's seat which was kind of
interesting um so you think it's almost
real but maybe is this one I should you
know what I should I should prepare
better for these periscopes yeah oh wow
look he's wearing VR headset um so a few
things about this there is actually a oh
yeah yeah it's at 0 1 yeah Linus tech
tips drove it ass
come on YouTube search come through for
me oh yeah Wow well that's really like
look at how there's like a thing around
the car this is like a Logan Paul move
man well it handles complicated tasks
like maintaining an appropriate speed
and following distance relative to other
cars merging so a few things look right
there do you see that guy in the
passenger seat he is driving the car he
literally has his hand on a joystick
driving the car this is not a level 4
autonomous car this is putting a driver
in the passenger seat right this is
absurd guys it's the current year that
we still let companies get away with
this kind of stuff ok driving there's
another video where you see all the
surround
cars actually being Renault cars as well
they put the sensors in other cars this
is a completely fake demo but not in a
really really look the guy's got is his
hand okay look I move his hand right
there it's on a joystick it's not for
security reasons you have security
reasons you know you have like an e-stop
for security reasons all right you don't
have a joystick which the guy is costing
Lucas got his hand he's like moving it
well the car drives so this one this
this one drove me crazy we're going back
a little bit but I'll actually show you
one of the demos that's that's more
impressive than that almost everything
coming out today go to Auto X so this is
a famous Princeton computer vision guy
we're looking at this one again
yesterday so this one it is hard-coded
paths but they actually did it using
cheap cameras um so you can see the two
cameras on the front there my
understanding is they're running hard
slim and they're using orb slam to
localize and then they're just following
the path with that which is pretty cool
actually that they actually made that
work robotics I've heard that name let's
check it out let's go through what they
might have is a leader in game changing
remote control road-ready can i buy one
let's watch the video I love watching
the videos Cabana is zero day I always
want to be one of those like you two
guys you dude watches other people's
YouTube videos and comments on them I do
they have sound oh okay I don't think
that they need a better video editing to
even we put sound in our videos I don't
know
this doesn't really show you anything
like okay
they put a lighter on the roof by the
way always watch out for this and you
know I like them for the most part but
I'm like voyage is notorious about this
voyage will focus extensively on what
their car looks like um for reference
those you don't know voyage I like the
guy
but voyage right Wow
well they're actually the first hit for
was pretty good of them um but yeah like
they're bigger the optics of
self-driving and maybe not so big on the
actual technology you can build
something that looks really impressive
all that takes is money the actual
working technology is what's hard to
build right if they're ever focusing on
like the user story it's probably
because they don't have the technology
so again we really have to give credit
to mobile I who gave a great talk about
what's actually possible I mean I think
he's fed up with the hype too like I
think he's he's fed up with uh you know
come on I'm wrong I'll change my opinion
but yeah so they're talking about this
this level 2 plus stuff front-facing
camera plus Road book I'm so Road book
is what mobile eye calls their HD Maps
but the thing about their HD maps which
is way better than everybody else is is
they're being made by the crowd just
like ours you've got to do it this way
it's the only way to scalably build HD
maps like the companies right now that
are spending millions of dollars to
build Maps notorious ones are like deep
map and TomTom like what they're
spending tons and tons of VC money on is
building 3d maps of the world there
isn't really a reason to do this because
building the map it's not useful unless
you can localize in the map right so you
build a lidar map of the world so this
is this is this is all crews does um
Cruz has built a Cruz automation Wow
they're not the first hit for Cruz but
voyage is the first hit for average get
on the SEO Bros do you know you know I
kind of like Cruz I mean they're all
right I tore apart their investor deck
because I hate things like that but uh
yeah so what Cruz is actually doing and
I'll show anything here but um they've
built a very precise lidar localizer so
we talked about Delfy Delfy is active
um Delphia has one of the most
impressive actually shippable demos
shippable is is questionable they're
using a lot of sensors they're fusing
them well together I mean they're good
at everything you would expect like a a
car OEM to be good at but yeah as far as
I was going I'm met with the del V guys
nice they're trying they're much much
better than like like Bosh Bosh has I
had met with the Bosh guy so you know
hopeless right
why does Schiffer not work and I ran we
didn't do anything special to make it
work or not work and maybe if I put
extra work in to make it work that's
illegal so I'm not sure can it do that
self-driving lift first rides this
recent yeah okay careful perfect the
Virg oh so this demo is in this demo
last year the Nvidia demo the Nvidia
demo was cute um I did talk about how
they cheat though you see those
buildings so this is it's a neural net
maybe that the same demo setup I'm so
first off this is a this is a Ford
Fusion by the way whenever you see a
Ford Fusion self-driving car understand
that this was not actually built by the
company it's sold by a company called
autonomous stuff so you had a keyboard
with no letters so it's kind of hard to
type so whenever you see a self-driving
car company with a Ford Fusion it's
built by this company autonomous stuff
or Lincoln MKZ it's the same car and
then the by wire is from this company
called data speed so these this is the
pic axis of self-driving cars yeah but
when you cut the Nvidia oh it was that
there was that let's close some of these
things
not by by deep map Oh torque yeah I
don't know I don't really think much of
torque I haven't like seen anything from
them here here's yeah so they're using
they're using the building's they're
using the bill outputting the policy
directly so they probably had someone
drive like 20 test laps and then they
trained up a deep net I'm very similar
to if you've seen DIY Robo cars DIY Robo
cars is a bunch of people getting
together in Oakland yeah yeah yeah so
this is this is Octavio good the famous
deep learning guy but yeah he basically
just directly trained given the car sees
this this is what the network's shit out
but yeah it's it's it's the same thing
as Dave dad basically so let's go back
to this video but yeah there's no really
cheating with the buildings and the way
that you know this is they have a they
have a screen inside the car that shows
you what the activations are having
their own network I probably wouldn't
have picked up on it if they didn't have
this visualization thing but the
buildings make this task
I'm easier than it should be because
their camera doesn't have a wide field
of view it doesn't actually have a wide
in a field of view to make this turn but
you know I like in video the truth is
NVIDIA is another one of these companies
that's gonna succeed almost even if they
have no software if you have a car
company right now you are so dumb for
not sticking and video Hardware hooked
up to your cameras in your car our rav4
has four cameras that I'm sure it's
hooked up to a processor like you know
those from like the mid-2000s
this is just lob yeah I don't know why
they all rebrand right all right cute
demo if you come on I thought she was
cute so you get in I can't with
journalists like follow this kind of
crap to you put like a like a little
display in the back doesn't matter it's
all localization based okay
I mean what's really important to look
at here is you can ignore all the crap
just look at their display cuz their
display and like little subtleties in
the car give away a ton of stuff um so
yeah I mean these dots here done with
lidar you see they're visualizing this
light here as green they're probably
detecting that out here so the way that
they're doing lights is they have all
the lights hand coded in the map and
then there are it's not cool come on Tec
Tec is cool flashy demos all we split
the screen in the car and they press go
and then the driver actually stepped on
the gas pedal come on guys oh all the
dahle DS alright come on stop with the
gimmicks different ways on a screen
let's see what's real here
histogram based live attacks almost
anything like that but yeah yeah they
are good about not having having wobbly
stuff but they're not using the
landlines they're using vocalization
okay so that one's kind of interesting
you can see when they do that lane
change the lanes snap from the left
right to the the other ones I mean
they're using mobile life for that
always Sam has almost all the light Maps
so yeah the it's a it's a having knowing
which intersection the light is act you
have to know with a very high level of
precision where to stop and where the
light actually is in like that all right
I think we're done people are coming
into work oh yeah no but what I've heard
like they have serious meetings where
they talk about us and they're like what
are we gonna do about comma because
we're not you know you can't buy me out
we will you start using the calendar
stops the red light but figuring out
where to stop is hard yes I'll flip you
guys background everyone's coming into
work so I should I should sign off but
yeah these companies consider comma
competitor yeah I do um no and you know
we're dark horse right like every other
company you know think oh well we could
just partner with them no like you can't
partner with me you have to be honest
with me you have to be like
straightforward I'm not down to like
join this little cabal of why don't we
all sit here while the technology
doesn't progress I'm here to make the
technology progressed you know mobile I
want to watch one of the best talks in
self-drive
cars watch the cvpr Mobileye keynote it
really is great and you know I've
missing mobile I'd do anything like that
before I always wonder if like the fall
the mobile I'd Tesla falling out had
something to do with with influencing uh
mobile I'd actually go and do that but
uh yeah thanks for joining
I'll be little more organized for the
next one of these but I think I'm shut
out to all the companies out there
you're not gonna get away with hype
anymore we're we're really here to bust
the hype we're really like if you if you
try to get away with posting a video of
bullshit I'll tear you apart I'll tear
you apart because hype is doing no good
for this field
um it's putting money in the wrong
places it's putting hope in the wrong
places it's making the wrong
partnerships we are here to destroy hype
hey hey you know 9/11 is bad anyone who
talks about that shit banned how big is
my DK large my donkey kong is is real
large man no truth but hype hype is down
with hype this is 2018 we're not gonna
stand for it you know what the comment
motto is for this year join us or die
and when I say join us I don't mean
partner with us I mean like if you're a
mapping company out there right now I'm
a hater on the hater
no it's we're bustin fake news man I
have deep love for technology and for
making things that actually work we do
offer for internships summer internships
apply give me give me a job at a comment
at AI hey man
I just want this stuff to work you know
and that's that's kind of what we're
here to do so your fake news get ready
to be to be chopped up or no I see you
with that joystick in the passenger seat
right that's that's maybe the ultimate
joke reward and maybe the mobile eye
gets the true-to-life award I cool
thanks for joining team karma yeah TM
Carla yeah join our team bro team kama
pro team kama we are the strongest
self-driving car team on the Internet
thank you for joining me in this
periscope
I love yelling it feels great I know why
Logan Paul does this peace out